[{"question":"<p><strong>A major liability of a commercial bank arise from<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Customers deposits","Loans and advances","Overdrafts","Staff allowances"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Retailers in an economy perform the function of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Production","Exchange","Distribution","Investment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a sole proprietorships the decision are made by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Government","Board of directors","Owner","Shareholders"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The meaning of wage-price spiral is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Demand pull and cost push inflation pulling each other in different","Demand pull and cost push intensifying each other","That wages and price are rising at a proportional rate","That demand pull and cost push inflation increase employment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following enterprise does not pursue the<\/strong><br \/><strong>sole objective of profit maximization<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Roads Nig Ltd","Union bank of Nigeria Ltd","Power holding & company of Nigeria","Kingsway Nigeria Ltd"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Palm oil industry is located in Edo state because the<\/strong><br \/><strong>state<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Imports raw material for oil industry","Is a palm tree growing area","Government does not engage land for other crops","Land is suitable for oil"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Disequilibrium in the balance of payments means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Imports of the country exceeding its export","Deficit in the trade balance","Capital flowing out of the country exceeds the capital flowing into the country","Overall deficit or surplus in the current account and capital account of the balance of payment."],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Full employment is a situation in which<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Every adult is employed","All adult who can work are employed","Only the disable are not employed","All those who are able and eligible to work can find employment"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>PHCN as a public corporation is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Duopoly","A power-generating industry in Nigeria","A monopoly","A mono polistically competitive industry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Demand for a factor of production is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A composite demand","A joint demand","A derived demand","An elasticity demand"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differential product is the characteristic feature of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Perfect competition","Pure competition","Monopoly","Monopolistic competition"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The channel for food distribution in Nigeria consists of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Producers wholesalers and retailers","Producers and consumers","producers and processor","Farmers processors and consumers"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>&nbsp;One disadvantage of sole proprietorships is its<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Limited liability","High profits","High sense of ownership","Low credit rating"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>For two substitute goods, the cross elasticity of<\/strong><br \/><strong>demand is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Greater than one but less than two","Zero","Negative","Positive"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a determinant of the<\/strong><br \/><strong>size of economically active population<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Age structure","Occupation of workers","Proportion of men to women","Efficiency of labour force"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The economic goal of public utilities is to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Maximize profit","Expand assets","Minimize cost","Provide essential services"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The most important characteristic of money is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Portability","Intrinsic value","Acceptability","Usefulness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a feature of economic underdevelopment of a country?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["large number of high income earners relative to the population","high annual income for the few","high incidence of poverty","high infant mortality rate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given the present state of the Nigerian economy<\/strong><br \/><strong>which of the following measurers will promote a more<\/strong><br \/><strong>rapid economic development<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Complete dependence on oil exports","Concentration on agricultural exports","Diversification of the economy","Introduction of nuclear energy in Nigeria"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following except ONE, are the differences<\/strong><br \/><strong>between international trade and internal trade<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Differences in currency","Government control","Mobility of factors of production","Exchange of goods and services"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The central bank instrument of control does NOT&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>include<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Open market operations","Moral suction","Selective credit control","Printing banknotes"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The basic principle of co-operative societies are those&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Workers ownership and worker control","Sole proprietorship","Partnership","Denying of credit facilities to members"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Generally property taxes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are borne entirely by landlords","Cannot be shifted in the long run","Are borne only by renters","Are born by all (renter, owner-occupiers and landlords)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The population level that yields the maximum output<\/strong><br \/><strong>when combined with available resources is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dependent population","Maximum population","Active population","Optimum population"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Retailers in an economy perform the function of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Production","Exchange","Distribution","Investment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a sole proprietorships the decision are made by the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Government","Board of directors","Owner","Shareholders"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Wage-price spiral means when?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Demand pull and cost push inflation are pulling each other in different directions","Demand pull and cost push are intensifying each other","Wages and price are rising at a proportional rate","Demand pull and cost push inflation increase employment"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following enterprise does not pursue the<\/strong><br \/><strong>sole objective of profit maximization?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Roads Nig Ltd","Union bank of Nigeria Ltd","Power holding & company of Nigeria","Kingsway Nigeria Ltd"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Palm oil industry is located in Edo state because the<\/strong><br \/><strong>state<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Imports raw material for oil industry","Is a palm tree growing area","Government does not engage land for other crops","Land is suitable for oil"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Disequilibrium in the balance of payments means<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Imports of the country exceeding its export","Deficit in the trade balance","Capital flowing out of the country exceeds the capital flowing into the country","Overall deficit or surplus in the current account and capital account of the balance of payment"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Full employment is a situation in which<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Every adult is employed","All adult who can work are employed","Only the disable are not employed","All those who are able and eligible to work can find employment"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>PHCN as a public corporation is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Duopoly","A power-generating industry in Nigeria","A monopoly","A monopolistically competitive industry"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Demand for a factor of production is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A composite demand","A joint demand","A derived demand","An elasticity demand"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Differential product is the characteristic feature of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Perfect competition","Pure competition","Monopoly","Monopolistic competition"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The channel for food distribution in Nigeria consists of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Producers wholesalers and retailers","Producers and consumers","Producers and processor","Farmers processors and consumers"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>One disadvantage of sole proprietorships is its<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Limited liability","High profits","High sense of ownership","Low credit rating"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>For two substitute goods, the cross elasticity of<\/strong><br \/><strong>demand is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Greater than one but less than two","Zero","Negative","Positive"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is NOT a determinant of the<\/strong><br \/><strong>size of economically active population<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Age structure","Occupation of workers","Proportion of men to women","Efficiency of labour force"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The economic goal of public utilities is to<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Maximize profit","Expand assets","Minimize cost","Provide essential services"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The most important characteristic of money is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Portability","Intrinsic value","Acceptability","Usefulness"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following is not a feature of economic underdevelopment of a country?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["large number of high income earners relative to the population","high annual income for the few","high incidence of poverty","high infant mortality rate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given the present state of the Nigerian economy<\/strong><br \/><strong>which of the following measurers will promote a more<\/strong><br \/><strong>rapid economic development<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Complete dependence on oil exports","Concentration on agricultural exports","Diversification of the economy","Introduction of nuclear energy in Nigeria"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following except one are the differences&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>between international trade and internal trade<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Differences in currency","Government control","Mobility of factors of production","Exchange of goods and services"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The central bank instrument of control does NOT<\/strong><br \/><strong>include<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Open market operations","Moral suction","Selective credit control","Printing"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The basic principle of co-operative societies are those<\/strong><br \/><strong>of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Workers ownership and worker control","Sole proprietorship","Partnership","Denying of credit facilities to members"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Generally property taxes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are borne entirely by landlords","Cannot be shifted in the long run","Are borne only by renters","Are born by all (renter, owner-occupiers and landlords)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The population level that yields the maximum output<\/strong><br \/><strong>when combined with available resources is known as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Dependent population","Maximum population","Active population","Optimum population"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"}]